Jordan Carlen

 $Smyrna,\ TN\mid M:\ 615-605-0070\mid Email:\ \underline{this is jordanc@gmail.com}\mid \underline{https://www.linkedin.com/in/jordancarlen/normalicational-emails}$

Summary

Analyst with experience in data engineering and business analytics. Strong mathematical background and experience using time-series analysis, predictive modeling, and data processing to solve challenging business problems. Involved in Python open-source community and passionate about machine learning.

Skills

Python, Microsoft Excel, SQL, R, Microsoft Power BI, Tableau, C++, Jupyter Notebooks, Tensorflow, AWS

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, August 2018 to December 2022

Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, Tennessee

Work Experience

Data Support Engineer

UBS Financial Services, Nashville, TN

August 2021 to Present

- Created data-driven models for data retrieval processes with Python and Jupyter Notebooks for improved FX transactions. Implemented production-ready code for a 9% improvement to access classification accuracy.
- Collaborated with investment banking divisions for day-to-day analysis to provide solutions for Azure data stream architecture and evolving trading technologies, leveraging strong communication skills to effectively present reports to multi-national teams.

Process Analyst Intern

Penske Logistics, Smyrna, TN June 2021 to August 2021

- Utilized Excel, Tableau, and other analytical tools to resolve stock shortages and assist in developing and presenting customer analytics, KPIs, and solution proposals during internal and external meetings.
- Contributed to team's knowledge pool of SQL on client systems, leading to a better understanding of data retrieval and improved monthly report speed by 16%.

Projects

Research Analysis, Middle Tennessee State University

August 2020 to December 2020

Maintained ML data streaming to model young children's performance in understanding computer science topics
through a game-based learning module with Tensorflow and Keras library. Provided visualizations with Tableau
based on documented findings and presented reports to heads of university departments. Results lead to enhanced
understanding of child development with algorithmic thinking.

Media Site Analysis, Middle Tennessee State University

March 2018 to November 2019

- Maintained ETL over 500,000 movies and other media from AWS big data warehouse containing messy data for site which allowed statistical querying and media strategy development.
- Employed Python Pandas, Numpy, Excel, and additional analytical software tools to organize and clean structured data for user development. This led to an increase in positive user reviews by over 24%.

Certifications

- DAS-C01 Amazon Web Services Certified Data Analytics
- MLS-C01 Amazon Web Services Machine Learning
- MS-70-461 Querying Microsoft SQL Server